Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence (Box 1-18)
  - Gick, Bryan, 1996-1998; 22 items (Box 7)
    The Harvey / Demus Creation / Tekanawita story in Oneida including some text in Oneida with English translation and a complete English translation.
  - Giertler, P. Engelbert-K., 1969; 3 items (Box 7)
    The Siriono Grammar of P. Fr. Anselmo Schermair and the Siriono kinship system.
  - Gilbert, W. H., 1957; 1 item (Box 7)
    The relation of speech and speech families to social origins.
  - Gillespie, John D., 1960-1962; 3 items (Box 7)
    Gillespie's work on his Cherokee grammar and dictionary; Caddoan-Iroquois-Chibchan-Cuna-Quechua comparisons.
  - Gillespie, John W., 1950-1952; 9 items (Box 7)
    Gillespie's work on Oklahoma Cherokee and Wyandot; working with Gertrude Kurath on Cherokee music.
  - Gillin, John L., 1951; 2 items (Box 7)
    The death of Edward Alsworth Ross and a memorial fund in his honor.
  - Gillispie, Charles C., 1987; 1 item (Box 7)
    FGL's election to the APS.
  - Gilpatric, Chadbourne, 1950; 14 items (Box 7)
    Conference on future directions for linguistic research, particularly with regard to semantics. Includes: manuscripts of Charles F. Hockett's "Communication Theory, Language, and Meaning" and Emile Benveniste's "A Proposal for a Discussion on the Problems of Meaning".
  - Gingerich, Owen, and Anthony F. Aveni, 1985; 1 item (Box 7)
    An international conference on archaeoastronomy.
  - Gladwin, Thomas, 1958-1969; 6 items (Box 7)
    Borrowing Gladwin's copy of volume II of Malinowski's Coral Gardens and Their Magic.
  - Glen, Edmund S., 1957; 1 item (Box 7)
    Linguistic vs. anthropological analyses of kinship systems.
  - Goddard, R. H. Ives, III, 1971-1993; 9 items (Box 7)
    Requesting that FGL write the chapter on the history of the study of North American Indian languages for the Handbook of North American Indians; other persons who might do the history chapter; Wallace Chafe's article on Seneca for the Handbook.
  - Goethals, Peter, 1958-1971, n.d.; 23 items (Box 7)
    Goethals' dissertation, Community and Kindred in Upland West Sumbawa (east Indonesia); jobs.
  - Goetze, Albrecht, 1961; 2 items (Box 7)
    A rumor that FGL was interested in the curatorship of the Babylonian Collection.
  - Goggin, John M., 1949-1950; 5 items (Box 7)
    Proposed fieldwork on Seminole by Goggin and FGL.
  - Goldensohn, Max, 1966; 1 item (Box 7)
    Goldensohn's desire to collect the 200-word "core vocabulary" for several languages of Gabon.
  - Goldschmidt, Walter, 1951-1952; 2 items (Box 7)
    Recordings of "primitive and native music" for use in a series of radio broadcasts.
  - Goldstine, Herman H., 1987; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Goodenough, Ward H., 1954-1971; 24 items (Box 7)
    Publications; jobs; FGL's contribution to the Festschrift for George P. (Pete) Murdock.
  - Goodenough, Ward H., and McGraw Hill, 1963-1966; 22 items (Box 7)
    Publications. Includes a typed manuscript and galley proofs of FGL's "A Formal Account of the Crow and Omaha-Type Kinship Terminologies."
  - Goodglass, Harold, 1958; 1 item (Box 7)
    Aphasic speech.
  - Goodwin, Diane, 1958; 2 items (Box 7)
    Bibliographical information on art among the Eastern Woodland Indians.
  - Gorbet, Larry, 1971; 1 item (Box 7)
    The Cherokee syllabary.
  - Gould, Peter H.; Robert O. Gould; and William Gould, 1986-1993; 3 items (Box 7)
    Their father's book.
  - Gould, Toni S. (Mrs. David H.), 1957; 8 items (Box 7)
    Publication of a book by Catherine Stern on a phonetic method of teaching reading.
  - Graburn, Nelson H. H., 1964-1971; 7 items (Box 7)
    Reprinting some of FGL's papers in Readings in Kinship and Social Structure edited by Graburn.
  - Grace, George W., 1962; 3 items (Box 7)
    Pawnee kinship terms.
  - Grady, John Marshall, 1965-1984, n.d.; 25 items (Box 7)
    Study of differential social change in neighboring villages in Mexico; personal updates; Grady's education issues; proposal for the study of "The Social Organization and Consequences of Ward Politics: Boston, 1926-1951".
  - Granberry, Julian, 1962-1984; 9 items (Box 7)
    Granberry's work on Florida Seminole, Zuni, and Onondaga; career changes; asking permission to use FGL's name in a comic strip.
  - Grayhorse, Tyrone, 1990; 1 item (Box 7)
    Producing recordings of Tuscarora for Grayhorse.
  - Graymont, Barbara, 1965-1994; 24 items (Box 7)
    Graymont's work on Tuscarora; Hewitt's "Cheroki" manuscript. Includes: some hymns in Tuscarora, most with English translation; photocopy of Franz Boas' "Notes on the Iroquois Language"; photocopy of Duane H. King's "Who Really Discovered the Cherokee-Iroquois Linguistic Relationship"; photocopies of 2 letters between J. Owen Dorsey and J. N. B. Hewitt regarding Athapascan and Algonkin.
  - Greenberg, Joseph H., 1953-1987; 9 items (Box 7)
    Publications; meetings; request that FGL fill in a word list with words from Iroquoian languages; Greenberg's appointment as a Guest Fellow of Berkeley College, Yale University; FGL election to the National Academy of Sciences and the APS.
  - Gregersen, Edgar, 1960-1983; 4 items (Box 7)
    Job possibilities; materials on East African languages; ancient Egyptian kinship.
  - Greimas, A. J., 1970-1971; 3 items (Box 7)
    L'Association Internationale de Semiotique. In French.
  - Gruber, Jacob W., 1965-1967; 3 items (Box 7)
    Horatio Hale; membership of Tutelo in Siouan.
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1959, n.d.; 9 items (Box 7)
    FGL's grant application for "Studies in the language and oral literature of the Iroquois".
  - Guizzetti, German Fernandez, 1966; 2 items (Box 8)
    Whether or not FGL will attend the 37th International Congress of Americanists in Argentina.
  - Gulick, John, 1958-1966; 8 items (Box 8)
    Cherokee-Iroquois Symposium at the 1958 AAA meeting; HRAF directors' meeting in New Haven.
  - Gursky, Karl-Heinz, 1961; 1 item (Box 8)
    Swadesh's "network theory" of linguistic relationship.
  - Guthe, Alfred K., 1953-1959; 6 items (Box 8)
    Iroquoian languages.
  - Haas, Mary R., 1941-1976; 50 items (Box 8)
    FGL's work on Oneida, Cherokee, and Pawnee; recording 25 double sided 10-inch records mainly of Cherokee but 1 of Natchez; Haas' work on Siamese (Thai); Iroquoian-Caddoan connections; similarities between Tunica and Iroquoian; Zellig Harris' work on Cherokee and Moraccan Arabic; conventions for representing voiceless aspirated and unaspirated stops; numerals; naming days of the week; proto-Gulf; Iroquoian reconstructions for 'water'; Edison cylinder recordings of Kutchin; death of Morris Swadesh; John Dunn Hunter's Manners and Customs of Indian Tribes. Includes: manuscript of Haas' comments on FGL's "Iroquois-Cherokee Linguistic Relations".
  - Hall, Robert L., 1992; 2 items (Box 8)
    Hall's work in progress A Parade of Silent Footsteps. Includes draft of chapter 10, "Eleazer Williams, Mohawk Between Two Worlds."
  - Hallowell, A. Irving, 1950-1962; 5 items (Box 8)
    Offprints; invitation to FGL to present a paper at the 50th anniversary celebration of The Philadelphia Anthropological Society.
  - Halverson, Emilio, Rev. and Mrs., 1950-1951; 5 items (Box 8)
    News from Brazil; personal updates.
  - Hamell, George R., 1979-1990; 29 items (Box 8)
    Iroquois culture, particularly Seneca; possible association between Tawiskala and (Nahuatl) Tlahuiskalpantekuhtli; names and descriptive terms for "Under(water) World Grandfathers" in Iroquoian and Siouan. Includes draft of Hamell's "Pieces of Dreams and Ancestors", "Tawiskala Section".
  - Hamilton, Edward P., 1958; 1 item (Box 8)
    FGL's study of Indian place names in the Champlain Valley.
  - Hammel, Eugene A., 1962-1971; 46 items (Box 8)
    Conference at Stanford University and special issue of American Anthropologist on componential analysis; Quechua kinship and marriage; kinship systems and terminologies.
  - Hammond, Hope, 1949; 3 items (Box 8)
    Mohawk and Oneida word for "end of the trail"; musings on the fate of the Mohawks.
  - Hammond, Norman, 1975-1982; 2 items (Box 8)
    Inviting FGL to contribute to a volume in honor of J. Eric S. Thompson; Maya dates and glyphs.
  - Hamp, Eric P., 1958-1959; 5 items (Box 8)
    FGL's Iroquois-Cherokee paper.
  - Hanks, William F., 1986-1987; 3 items (Box 8)
    Status of contributions to a volume on colonial Yucatec; uses of ahau 'king' and tepal 'majesty' in Yucatec including examples.
  - Hansen, Alfred W., 1965; 2 items (Box 8)
    Bibliographical references on Mohegan-Pequot.
  - Hardman-de-Bautista, Martha James, 1964; 2 items (Box 8)
    Quechua kinship.
  - Harmon, Carlo, Rev. and Mrs., 1950-1952; 4 items (Box 8)
    FGL's work on Bororo, Umotina, Bakairi, and Paressi in Brazil; the Harmons' work at the Aquidauanaa Bible School (Brazil).
  - Harrell, Richard S., 1960; 2 items (Box 8)
    FGL's article in "Monograph 12" from Georgetown University.
  - Harrington, M. R., 1954; 1 item (Box 8)
    Establishing a publication fund in honor of Frederick Webb Hodge.
  - Harris, Alfred, 1969-1970; 10 items (Box 8)
    FGL's giving the 1970 Lewis Henry Morgan Lectures at the University of Rochester and his topic of kinship systems.
  - Harris, Zellig S., 1946-1949; 9 items (Box 8)
    A Phillips Fund grant to FGL for work on Oneida; details (including examples) with regard to the Oneida dictionary to be produced under the grant; evaluation of "original papers in connection with the Cherokee Indian Nation".
  - Harrison, H. P., 1963; 8 items (Box 8)
    Returning books to the Yale University library.
  - Haugen, Einar, 1972; 2 items (Box 8)
    FGL's participation in the golden anniversary symposium "American Indian Languages and American Linguistics" at Berkeley.
  - Haviland, William A., 1965; 3 items (Box 8)
    16th Century Maya kinship systems.
  - Heady, Gordon, 1988-1990; 3 items (Box 8)
    Maya calendar software.
  - Heath, Dwight B., 1961-1974; 11 items (Box 8)
    Invitations to speak at Brown University; Heath's sabbatical in Costa Rica; a possible Mixtec codex which Heath found in Oaxaca.
  - Heckel, Robert L., 1962-1963; 5 items (Box 8)
    FGL's paper, "A Formal Account of a Kinship System," given at The New York Academy of Sciences.
  - Heijtz, Sven, 1966; 2 items (Box 8)
    FGL's work in Mato Grosso.
  - Hein, M. A., 1952; 1 item (Box 8)
    Grasses and legumes adapted to Brazil.
  - Heinrich, Albert, 1961; 3 items (Box 8)
    Eskimo kinship.
  - Heise, Gerhard, 1989; 2 items (Box 8)
    Professional opinions and relationships between Swadesh and Bloch, Bloomfield and Sapir, and Boas and Whorf.
  - Hellmuth, Nicholas M., 1967-1988; 5 items (Box 8)
    Maya kinship.
  - Helmig, Thomas, 1979; 2 items (Box 8)
    Notes on Helmig's dissertation on kinship.
  - Henderson, John S., 2 items (Box 8)
    NEH proposal for "Maya Hieroglyphic Writing: Cosmology and Astronomy in the Precolumbian Codices."
  - Hendon, Rufus S., 1966-1971; 5 items (Box 8)
    Employment; Hendon's work on his dissertation, a linguistic analysis of Negeri Sembilan Malay.
  - Henry, Leo R., 1986; 1 item (Box 8)
    Asking that FGL tape the Opening and Closing addresses in Tuscarora for them so they can have their own longhouse.
  - Henry, Ray, and Bill Woodbury, 1991; 3 items (Box 8)
    Details of translating the Opening and Closing addresses into Tuscarora.
  - Herskovits, Melville J., 1948; 3 items (Box 8)
    Inviting FGL to apply for a teaching position at Northwestern University.
  - Hetzel, Debbie, Janice Molloy, and Jenny Bauman, 1980; 3 items (Box 8)
    Sixth graders inquiring about the abandonment of Maya cities; FGL's response.
  - Hewson, John, 1976; 1 item (Box 8)
    Inquiring as to the identity of the Native American language of a vocabulary at the end of Cartier's narrative of his 1534 voyage.
  - Heyward, Roland, 1982; 1 item (Box 8)
    Discussion of and bibliographical references for Catawba.
  - Hickerson, Nancy P., 1972; 1 item (Box 8)
    FGL's 1959 BAE Iroquois symposium paper on the separation of Cherokee and other languages.
  - Hill, Archibald A., 1951-1967; 13 items (Box 8)
    FGL as liason between AAA and LSA; LSA affairs; linguistic sessions at AAA.
  - Hill, George W., 1941; 2 items (Box 8)
    Offer of part time employment at the University of Wisconsin to FGL; FGL's pending entry into the U. S. Army.
  - Hill, Roberta, 1977; 2 items (Box 8)
    Oneida language materials; learning to speak Oneida.
  - Hockett, Charles F., 1947-1989; 11 items (Box 8)
    A laboratory of Iroquoian linguistics at Cornell University to be run by FGL; Algonquian; Umotina.
  - Hoffman, Bernard G., 1955-1962; 9 items (Box 8)
    St. Lawrence Iroquois; Micmac; Russian work on Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Hoffmann, Hans, 1955-1962; 18 items (Box 8)
    Culture-personality investigations; differences in the behavior of the Eskimo and the Cree.
  - Hofling, Andy, 1985; 3 items (Box 8)
    FGL's contribution to the hieroglyph volume in memory of Marshall Durbin.
  - Hoijer, Harry, 1952-1970, n.d.; 11 items (Box 8)
    Opening at UCLA; conference on ethnolinguistics; FGL's agreement to serve on the Viking Fund Medal and Award Committee; reviews of works on Indian place names of Maryland and Champlain Valley; location of Sapir's Athapaskan and other Native American Language data.
  - Holbrook, Bruce, 1974-1978; 7 items (Box 8)
    Holbrook's field work on Chinese preventive medicine in Taiwan; folklore of Nova Scotia.
  - Holden, J. H., 1953; 3 items (Box 8)
    Request to borrow equipment to record phrases and music of several languages including Warao, Arawak, Acawai, Carib, Macusi, Wapisiana, Arecuna, etc.
  - Holmer, Nils M., 1959; 2 items (Box 8)
    Inquiring about FGL's materials on Cherokee.
  - Holmes, Ruth B., 1972; 3 items (Box 8)
    Bibliography of works on Iroquoian.
  - Hook, Sidney, 1967-1968, n.d.; 12 items (Box 8)
    Program on "Culture and Language" at the annual meeting of the New York University Institute of Philosophy.
  - Hopkins, Nicholas A., 1967-1988; 6 items (Box 8)
    Collecting plant names in Mayan languages; Tzotzil kinship terminology; Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Hoppan, Jean-Michel, 1990; 1 item (Box 8)
    Hoppan's work on Maya hieroglyphs from ceramics.
  - Horn, Laurence R., 1992; 12 items (Box 8)
    Restructuring the Faculty of Arts and Sciences at Yale University; proposal that the Linguistics Department be "discontinued". Includes several newspaper clippings about Yale.
  - Horton, Thomas, Mr. and Mrs., 1950; 1 item (Box 8)
    FGL's recent trip to Mato Grosso, Brazil.
  - Houston, Stephen D., 1983-1984; 7 items (Box 8)
    Houston's work on Maya hieroglyphs in Gratemala.
  - Howells, W. W., 1948-1950; 5 items (Box 8)
    Possible teaching position at the University of Wisconsin; Swadesh's work on Mahican.
  - Hsu, Francis L. K., 1960-1961; 4 items (Box 8)
    FGL's pending promotion at Yale; job offer from Northwestern University.
  - Huden, John C., 1960-1962; 11 items (Box 9)
    Translation of Algonquian names; Mohawk place names.
  - Hughes, Charles A., 1955-1957; 2 items (Box 9)
    Hughes' work on Mohawk.
  - Hunt, Earl B., n.d.; 2 items (Box 9)
    The ability of English speakers to distinguish "certain released and unreleased stops".
  - Huttar, George L., 1990; 2 items (Box 9)
    SIL's Museum of the Alphabet, Waxhaw, North Carolina.
  - Huxley, Frederick C., 1969-1986; 6 items (Box 9)
    Huxley's work in Lebanon; his dissertation. Includes a photocopy of Huxley's "Contrasting Semantic Structures in English and Arabic: Problem and Promise in Second-Language Learning".
  - Hymes, Dell, 1957-1968; 41 items (Box 9)
    FGL speaking to classes at Harvard University; psycholinguistics, linguistic anthropology; poetry; glottochronology; Cherokee-Iroquois relationship; meetings, symposia; publications; the Linguistics Department at UC Berkeley; Nimuendaju's German manuscript on the Apinaye.
  - Illius, Bruno, 1987; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - International Congress of Americanists, 1949-1970; 17 items (Box 9)
    Conference information. Includes an abstract of FGL's 1964 paper, "Some Aspects of the Inca Kinship System".
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1952-1963, n.d.; 12 items (Box 9)
    Conference information. Includes an abstract of FGL's 1964 paper "The Structure of the Latin Kinship System and its Relation to Roman Social Organization."
  - International Congress of Linguists, 1957, n.d.; 3 items (Box 9)
    Conference information.
  - Iroquois Correspondence, 1988-1997; 15.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Iroquois Indian Museum, 1995; 2 items (Box 9)
    14th annual Iroquois Indian Festival.
  - Jackson, Jean, 1968; 3 items (Box 9)
    Jackson's proposed fieldwork in Brazil.
  - Jackson, Mrs. James A., Jr., 1969; 2 items (Box 9)
    Spanish-to-Maya Motul dictionary.
  - Jacobson, Jerome, 1987; 2 items (Box 9)
    A pictograph at Alton, Illinois; meaning of the possibly Iroquoian word otkon.
  - Jakobson, Roman, 1952-1964; 4 items (Box 9)
    Offprints; recordings of Umotina.
  - Jelinek, Eloise Kerlin, 1957-1998; 3 items (Box 9)
    Papers on kinship systems; FGL's return to work on Oneida.
  - Jensen, M. Kloster, 1958; 4 items (Box 9)
    Tone languages.
  - John, Curtis R. (Tayokawe), 1991, n.d.; 4 items (Box 9)
    Oneida language materials and recordings; attempts to revive Oneida as a spoken language.
  - Johnson, Frederick, 1951; 1 item (Box 9)
    FGL's activities as liason between AAA and LSA.
  - Johnson, Grant W., 1959; 3 items (Box 9)
    Publication of FGL's work on Indian place names in the Champlain Valley.
  - Jones, Christopher, 1988; 2 items (Box 9)
    Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Jones, Tom, 1988, n.d.; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Joos, Martin, 1949-1966; 20 items (Box 9)
    Electronic aids to transcribing field recordings; Joos' Readings in Linguistics; reprints; obituary for Bernard Bloch.
  - Joralemon, Peter David, 1974-1977; 5 items (Box 9)
    His proposed study of Olmec art.
  - Jorgensen, Joseph G., 1964; 2 items (Box 9)
    A recording of Northern Ute being sent to FGL with details about the native consultant.
  - Juilland, Alphonse, 1975; 2 items (Box 9)
    Requesting an article from FGL for a Festschrift in honor of Joseph Greenberg's 60th birthday.
  - Justeson, John, 1977-1997, n.d.; 9 items (Box 9)
    Tables for solar and lunar eclipses from the Kudlek canon; Justeson's paper on the Tabascan long count system; syntax of Maya hieroglyphic writing; recovering glyphs on the La Mojarra stela (Xalapa). Includes: computer printout of Justeson's "The non-Maya calendars of Southern Veracruz and Tabasco and the antiquity of the civil and agricultural years"; tables of solar and lunar eclipses; computer printout of Justeson and William M. Norman's "A Reinterpretation of Some 'Auxiliary Verb' Constructions in Mayan Hieroglyphic Writing"; draft of paper by Justeson and Terrence Kaufman "A decipherment of epi-Olmec hieroglyphic writing" ("epi-Olmec", "pre-proto-Zoquean") which had been submitted to Science.
  - Kaldor, Susan, 1959; 1 item (Box 9)
    Requesting bibliographical information from FGL on English as a second language for South-East Asian students.
  - Kamma, F. C., 1962; 3 items (Box 9)
    Arranging for Kamma to give a lecture at Yale on the social anthropology of New Guinea.
  - Kaplan, Jonathan, 1992-1994; 4 items (Box 9)
    Kaplan's dissertation prospectus; symposium in honor of Michael Coe. Includes: Kaplan's dissertation prospectus, "Ancient Maya Rulership Through Time: History and Ideology at Kaminaljuyu and Tikal"; copy of Kaplan's paper, "Jeremias Lopez, A Ch'orti Maya from Jocotan, Guatemala" for the Coe symposium.
  - Katzner, Kenneth, 1970; 2 items (Box 9)
    Requesting from FGL a sample of an Iroquoian language with English translation. Includes a short sample of Navajo with English translation.
  - Kaufman, Terrence, 1968-1993; 3 items (Box 9)
    Kaufman's work and pending promotion; Mesoamerican month names.
  - Kay, Paul, 1963-1971; 11 items (Box 9)
    Kinship systems; FGL's being a discussant at an AAA symposium; analysis of Seneca kinship terms. Includes: draft of a paper [by Kay} on kinship which refers to FGL's analysis of Seneca kinship.
  - Kay Electric Company, 1958; 3 items (Box 9)
    A scale magnifier for the Kay sonagraph.
  - Keesing, Roger, 1962-1975, n.d.; 22 items (Box 9)
    Analysis of kinship systems.
  - Keller, Janet Dixon, 1991; 7 items (Box 9)
    Publication of FGL's 1990 Distinguished Lecture at AAA.
  - Kelley, Dave, 1962-1990; 7 items (Box 9)
    Maya calendar.
  - Kenny, Hamill, 1952-1966; 8 items (Box 9)
    The meaning and language of origin for Indian place names of Maryland: Antietam, Lonaconing, and Octoraro; request for an FGL article on Iroquoian names for the Names magazine.
  - Kensinger, Kenneth M., 1965; 3 items (Box 9)
    Kensinger's work on matrilocality and patrilineality in Amazonian groups.
  - Kerstetter, Rose, 1980; 2 items (Box 9)
    Kerstetter's script for a slide show on the Oneida. Includes a copy of the script.
  - Khera, Sigrid, 1969-1975; 7 items (Box 9)
    Khera's work on land inheritance in Austria; requests for recommendations.
  - Kidd, Kenneth E., 1958-1959; 4 items (Box 9)
    Tapes of Iroquoian languages from old cylinders.
  - Kilpatrick, Jack Frederich, 1962-1967; 11 items (Box 9)
    Kilpatrick's work on Cherokee; Cherokee morphology.
  - King, Duane H., 1971-1978; 3 items (Box 9)
    King's work on Cherokee; A Cherokee-Iroquois conference (1978).
  - Kinkade, M. Dale, 1973; 2 items (Box 9)
    Suggesting articles to be abstracted for publication in IJAL.
  - Kiputh, David O., 1979-1981; 4 items (Box 9)
    Requesting a photo of FGL for display at Yale's Peabody Museum.
  - Klein, Edward B., 1963-1965; 8 items (Box 9)
    Invitations to FGL to speak at seminars sponsored by the Psychology and Psychiatry Departments of the West Haven VA Hospital.
  - Knezevich, Eugene, 1989; 2 items (Box 9)
    A group photo including FGL (photo included)
  - Knoedler, M., and Co., 1953; 3 items (Box 9)
    Part of a letter requesting help in identifying Cherokee chiefs of the 18th century. Includes photos "Scyacust Ukah 1762" and "Three Cherokee Chiefs Sent to England in 1762".
  - Kremer, Jurgen, 1989; 1 item (Box 9)
    Kremer's work on glyphs at Palenque.
  - Kroeber Anthropological Society, 1963-1964; 7 items (Box 9)
    FGL's talk, "The Nature of the Inca Kinship System."
  - Kronenfeld, David B., 1967-1991; 9 items (Box 9)
    Kinship systems; requests for recommendations; the Anthropology program at the University of California, Riverside.
  - Kuipers, Aert H., 1952-1958, n.d.; 10 items (Box 9)
    Psychophysical parallelism; Qabardian materials sent to FGL; Georgian (Caucasian) language. Includes materials in Qabardian (Circassian, Caucasian) in Cyrillic script with Russian translation.
  - Kurath, Gertrude, 1956-1957; 5 items (Box 9)
    Iroquois conferences. Includes abstract of Kurath's paper "Iroquois Dance and Music Resistance to Western Nativisms."
  - Kurbjuhn, Kornelia, 1976-1995, n.d.; 20 items0 (Box 9)
    Personal matters; Kurbjuhn's work on Mesoamerican Ethnology, astronomy, and languages; Maya hieroglyphs. Includes a photocopy of Yu. V. Knorozov and G. G. Yershova, "An Inscription on a Sarcophagus at Palenque."
  - Kutsche, Paul, 1962; 2 items (Box 9)
    FGL's Cherokee field notebooks.
  - La Literaria, 1957; 6 items (Box 10)
    Purchase of Maya dictionaries.
  - Lacombe, Charles, 1989; 2 items (Box 10)
    Almanacs in the Maya codices; Maya calendars.
  - Ladefoged, Peter, 1966; 2 items (Box 10)
    An apicolabial stop in Yumatina.
  - Lamb, Weldon, 1977-1982; 4 items (Box 10)
    Interpretation of Maya glyphs.
  - Landar, Herbert, 1958-1959; 5 items (Box 10)
    Landar's work on Navajo syntax; a student applying to Yale.
  - Landy, David, 1957-1958; 6 items (Box 10)
    Landy's paper on Tuscarora.